ALEXANDER BURR

Email alex@alexburr.com
Web www.alexburr.com

LinkedIn alexanderburr
GitHub alexburr

Dribbble pokealex **JSFiddle** alexburr

SUMMARY

Software developer and user interface designer with over 20 years of experience in all phases of the software life cycle. A passion for creating a culture of design thinking and user experience focus. Enjoys opportunities to learn new technologies and new domains, and strives to foster sharing and mentorship between development colleagues. Experienced in Agile development with Scrum, works with a CI/CD mindset, and strives to establish a standard of quality and improvement in all areas of work.

COMPETENCIES & SKILLS

20+ years experience in web development, software engineering, and user interface design

Server-side programming: ASP.Net with C#, Java, PHP, ColdFusion

Client-side templating: C#: Razor, Nancy, PHP: Smarty

Unit testing: xUnit.net with Moq, Jest

Web frameworks: Spring Boot, ASP.Net MVC, Web API, Spring,

Codelgniter, ColdFusion on Wheels

Content management: Umbraco, WordPress, Textpattern, and

Cascade Server

Wireframing and design: Axure RP, Adobe Photoshop, Visio, Balsamiq

Client-side frameworks: React, AngularJS

Database experience: Oracle, SQL Server, MySQL, NoSQL

(MongoDB)

Version control: Git, Mercurial, Subversion, TFS

Environments: Windows/IIS/OpenShift and Linux/Apache

Project concepts: life cycle methodology, needs assessment and usability, information architecture, content strategy, SEO and

conversion, and analytics

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Developer, Mindex

May 2021-present

SOW position for payroll, HR and benefits outsourcing service provider. Work was primarily full-stack development projects, for both internal and customer-facing applications.

Maintained and expanded API microservices in Java Spring Boot Framework hosted on OpenShift.

Developed web user interfaces for employee retirement fund management, using AngularJS and React.

Software Engineer, Pharos Systems International June 2012–April 2021

Full-stack development of cloud print management solution's AWS EC2-hosted web interface, with C#, jQuery, Kendo UI, and React, RESTful .NET services.

Lead Web Developer, University of Rochester Medical Center July 2010—June 2012

Designed and developed web applications for use in various institutional business processes and workflows.

Senior Web Developer, University of Rochester Medical Center September 2007—June 2010

Production Manager, Cazbah September 2004—September 2007

Web Developer, Element K
October 2003–December 2003

Software Engineer, AHT June 2000–July 2002

ADDITIONAL PROJECTS

Groove Juice Swing

Ongoing

Content author, designer and developer for this website for a dance instruction group. Also designer/developer for various event websites, including https://www.groovejuiceswing.com and https://www.groovejuiceswing.com and https://www.groovejuiceswing.com and https://www.stompology.com.

Yehoodi

2009-2017

Designer/developer for this social website for a nationwide swing dance community. https://www.yehoodi.com

Pilcrow Music

Ongoing

Personal website for music projects, built with Hexo and hosted at Netlify. https://pilcrowmusic.com/

GitHub Projects

Ongoing

Multiple projects to assist in guitar playing, songwriting, bandleading, and crochet blanket pattern design, built on a variety of web technologies including React and HTML5. https://alexburr.github.io/

EDUCATION

Rochester Institute of Technology

BS in Information Technology (May 2000)

REFERENCES

Available upon request.